EPISODE 19
Deqing went to Kaifeng Court
to find out more.
It's said that he was imprisoned.
Lianghan, what does it mean
to be both the plaintiff
and the defendant?
It's quite confusing.
If Minister Yu abandoned his wife
to remarry,
he's the one who should be blamed.
Why is that the brother-in-law…
Mr. Du has been thrown into prison?
We only see fathers beating sons.
When have you ever seen
a son scold his own father?
He questioned his father
at the wedding banquet
and sued at the Yamen, accusing his father
of abandoning his wife to remarry.
What do you think he's doing?
- What?
- Being un-filial.
Yu Weiyi abandoned his wife,
leaving her and their son to wander.
After over 20 years of hardship,
can't he question his misconduct?
If not, then how can he uphold justice
for his wrongly deceased mother?
Is there any justice in this world?
What will the Kaifeng Court do about this?
Will they strip him of his honors
or penalize him with caning or exile him?
Since ancient times,
sons who accuse their fathers
are considered to offend the elder
and violate the duty of a son.
Based on the laws, once an accusation
is made, be it true or not,
the accusers shall get death by hanging.
- Hanging?
- No way.
Lady Cui, who killed a person,
only received a fine and caning.
Is Mr. Du's crime heavier than hers?
That is the elder offending the junior.
This is vice versa.
One gets palliated in the crime,
the other is doubly guilty.
They are different. According to the law,
Du Yangxi shall be sentenced to death.
Shouhua, I'm just talking nonsense.
Don't worry. He'll be okay.
You told me to say it.
Regarding fathers and sons
taking their disputes to court,
there are cases where officials took pity
on the junior and gave a lighter sentence.
After all, if the son gets killed,
who will take care of the elderly father?
The law also has exceptions.
I will go to Kaifeng Court early tomorrow
to wait for updates.
No one is allowed to go.
Mother.
Alright.
You've divorced, meaning
that you two have parted ways.
We've done best to take care
of his stepmother for him.
What? Do you want to exile with him?
Shouhua, you are engaged to someone else.
Listen to me. Don't meddle in this.
Get up and go back to your room.
- Get up.
- Mother.
Go back to your room.
Madam is right.
Before, he tried every mean
to divorce Shouhua.
Shut up. You fool, can't you see
he did so to drive Shouhua away,
in order not to implicate her?
That's right.
Shouhua almost got implicated
in this heinous crime.
At worst, we might be implicated
and get sentenced to death.
That was close.
After all this, I might have
to ask you to bury my body
and settle my deceased soul.
Kangning. I can't abandon Yuanming.
I must find a way to save him.
KAIFENG COURT PRISON
SHEN HUIZHAO
Mr. Du did so for his mother,
to fulfill the filial piety as a son.
His sincerity is really admirable.
Give my order.
Don't torture him, and treat him nicely.
Yes.
Do you want to plead for Mr. Du
at the imperial court?
No matter what, the law can't be violated.
How can I compromise the law of the Song
because of sympathy?
This case should be judged as the law.
Take a look.
These are all nice.
Everything is carefully chosen, showing
the Sang's caring of this marriage.
September is coming.
I want to discuss with the Sang family
to get the wedding done
before the end of this year.
Shouhua, this color looks good on you.
Does it look good? What do you think?
- Yes.
- It really does look good.
- It looks good.
- I got the news.
I got the news, Fuhui.
Madam, haven't you gone to the shop yet?
About that Du guy again? Is it worse?
No.
His Majesty asked the officials to discuss
the case again. Du might have some hope.
Really?
Once His Majesty
convenes the imperial assembly,
Yuanming's execution is imminent.
- No, no.
- Madam.
I ran into Mr. Sang at the gate,
so I invited him in.
Wait, Mr. Sang. You two are not supposed
to meet before the wedding.
No matter what, you should let
the matchmaker deliver the messages.
You can't break the rules.
Please step out first.
- Madam Li.
- I have a matter to discuss with Shouhua.
- You can't meet.
- Madam.
He has something to say.
- No. You can't break the rules.
- Madam.
Fuhui, what's wrong?
- My stomach hurts.
- Huh?
Help Fuhui to her room.
- It's not the time yet.
- Madam.
Fuhui, get back to your room.
- Go back to lie down.
- Hurry up.
- Help her go in.
- Madam.
- Be careful.
- Hurry. Go back and lie down.
- Help her go in.
- Fuhui.
- Be careful.
Why do you bring him here so directly?
If it weren't Fuhui,
you would get a good beating.
I didn't think that much.
- Mr. Sang.
- No need for further talk.
For the sake of our stepmother,
I won't abandon him. It is urgent now.
Officials have disagreements
about this case.
So, His Majesty held
the imperial assembly.
Why are you sure
he'll be sentenced to death?
I immediately rushed back
once I received the news.
I led for him everywhere.
There are many officials
sympathizing Yuanming.
But the courts
insist on the death penalty.
Especially Shen Huizhao
from the Kaifeng Court.
He filed three memorials
for the death penalty.
A Dali Supreme Court official told me
Shen Huizhao has been convincing
others these days
and won over
Magistrate and Remonstration officials.
I'm afraid that in this imperial assembly,
Yuanming's odds are not good.
Oh my!
What is the deep hatred
Mr. Shen has against Mr. Du?
Why does he have
to sentence Mr. Du to death?
Haode.
Haode, I…
KAIFENG COURT
Hey, you bureaucrat!
Are you forgetting how your mother
raised you? Ungrateful.
Poo!
- Who are you? Stop there.
- Alright.
- No need to mind her.
- Yes.
Is there no one who can save Du Yuanming?
The officials can't make
a unanimous decision.
What are they arguing about?
Yuanming sued his father for his mother,
repaying his mom but offending his father.
They are arguing about who is more
important, the father or the mother.
Of course, they are equally important.
It is pointless to argue about it.
No, it has a point.
In ordinary families,
there's no need to argue about this.
But in this case,
Yuanming sued his father for his mother.
He will be sentenced to death.
But if the mother is more important
than the father, then he might be saved.
The imperial court is full of men.
Naturally, they value their fathers more.
No one defends for Mrs. Xie,
who's died wrongly. It's so unfair.
Kangning, this is not true.
There are also officials
willing to defend Yuanming.
Kangning, do you still remember that joke
about Xie An taking a concubine?
Shouhua, you still have the mood
for a joke?
Grand Tutor Xie
wanted to take a concubine,
but his wife, Madame Liu,
didn't allow it. So, he had to ask
the men in the clan to convince his wife.
Those men used the poems,
Guan Ju and Zhong Si,
to advise Madame Liu not to be jealous.
Women should let their husbands
take concubines to thrive in the family.
Madame Liu asked who wrote the poems,
and those men replied, "Mr. Zhou."
Then, what was Madame Liu's response?
She said, "Mr. Zhou was a man.
If Mrs. Zhou wrote the poems,
she would never have said so."
- I understand.
- You mean…
The imperial court is full of men.
Yet some pretended
to value the mothers over the fathers.
Then, who did these people
intend to please?
The Empress Dowager.
There are chamberlains
coming and going in the Pan Restaurant.
I have to entrust this to you.
Kangning, rest assured.
I will figure it out.
It's easy to deliver messages, but it's
hard to convince the Empress Dowager.
Your Highness.
The Painting Academy delivered the artwork
Playful Dogs at the Imperial Garden
for you to appraise.
EMPRESS DOWAGER, LIU E
The painters of the Painting Academy
used to emulate Master Huang's brushwork,
pursuing the vibe of magnificence.
Yet they only imitated the style,
not the soul.
Your Highness,
you are discerning of talents.
This Mr. Chen, who came from the folk,
is indeed more lively and less rigid.
You went to fetch the painting.
Why do you look so mad?
Your Highness, when I went to get it,
I felt it was over-praised.
I'm afraid it won't meet
Empress Dowager's expectations.
I had some arguments with
the Painting Academy.
Something seems to be missing.
Your Highness, you are discerning.
The day lilies in the garden are missing.
Speaking of the reason behind it,
it relates to a strange case
in the imperial court.
Your Majesty, Yu Weiyi
abandoned his wife to remarry,
violating morality
and going against the law.
Removing him from his position
will be a light punishment.
As for Du Yangxi,
we always put fathers before mothers.
The Funeral Rites goes, if a father dies,
offsprings may wear weeds for three years.
If a mother dies, offspring may wear
mourning apparel for a year.
In mourning rites,
fathers are valued more than mothers.
Hence, fathers are honored above mothers.
As a son, Du Yangxi accused his father.
It's a civil case, not criminal.
Despite understandable reasons,
Yamen isn't the place for it.
But the fact that it is against the law,
Du Yangxi should be sentenced to death.
Your Majesty, please make a wise judgment.
Since all of you have reached a decision,
then this--
The Empress Dowager has arrived.
Greetings to the Empress Dowager.
- Greetings to the Empress Dowager.
- Save the formalities.
BALANCE AND HARMONY
I have heard
Your Majesty is reviewing the case
where Mr. Du accuses against his father.
Yes, Your Highness.
The Dali Supreme Court and Kaifeng Court
thought Du Yangxi should be hung to death.
But the Case Review Court and Ministry of
Punishments see it as excessive.
So, I had the discussion
with all officials.
Now, we have finally reached a conclusion.
We agree to the decision of Kaifeng Court
to sentence Du Yangxi to death.
I have heard Mr. Du
is quick-witted and talented.
Since you're having an imperial assembly,
why not listen to his explanation?
- Summon Du Yangxi immediately.
- Understood.
I am Du Yangxi.
Greetings to the Empress Dowager
and to the Emperor.
- Du Yangxi.
- No need to question him yet.
Let's see a painting first.
The splendor of the day lily
is like the love of a kind mother.
The Empress Dowager plays the role
of a father, supporting the emperor.
She presides over the imperial court
and commands respect from all.
Seeing the day lilies overshadowed
by that big tree,
she wouldn't ignore it.
On the day I toured the garden,
there were day lilies
blossoming everywhere.
But the painters said
the tree represents the father
and the day lily the mother.
The day lilies can't outshine the trees,
nor mothers surpass fathers.
They refused to paint it as it is.
How absurd and ridiculous!
Du Yangxi. I previously ordered someone
to inform you of all the discussions
in the imperial court.
What do you want to say?
Your Highness.
Officials say fathers are traditionally
honored over mothers since ancient times.
Yet the child is the combination
of the father and the mother.
The kindness of our parents
is hard to repay.
Since the Tang dynasty,
whether the father is present or not,
it's customary for a child
to mourn their mother for three years.
Even the laws can't prohibit this.
This shows what people really think.
Yet there are people who claim
the mother can't be honored as the father.
I dare not agree.
What you said makes sense.
If both parents should be equally honored,
the mother's love is as important
as the father's.
Then what crime do I commit
to accuse on behalf of my mother?
Your Majesty, since ancient times,
fathers have been honored.
Du Yangxi, you accused your father
on behalf of your mother,
then you're offending the honored one.
Death penalty it is.
Then, may I ask,
when a toddler is learning to speak,
does he call out "Mother" first?
One can only recognize the mother
and not the father when he's little.
Only after learning knowledge can one
distinguish superiors and inferiors.
Everyone fulfills their roles
and does their jobs.
Only then can the family and country
be stable and without worries.
If a son defies his father,
or a minister argues against his ruler,
everyone to be un-filial, disrespectful,
disloyal, and unchaste,
then how could a country
or a family be stable?
Ignoring the law when judging cases,
then what's the use of the law of Song?
Well said.
What Mr. Shen means is,
even birds know to love their mothers,
while a person who has learned
can lose his gratitude and kindness,
becoming worse than beasts.
Right.
The first word
a toddler utters is "Mother".
It's natural to honor the mothers.
Are there no children
who utter "Father" first?
Your Majesty.
My little child recognizes only me
and not his mother.
The first word he uttered was "Father".
Mother, the imperial assembly
has no conclusion yet.
Please do take good care of yourself.
It's all my fault.
I lied about who he was.
I shouldn't have let him go to the capital
to take the imperial examination.
It's all my fault.
Sangma.
Go prepare some incense and candles.
Mother wants to pray for Mr. Du.
Okay.
Mother, what Yangxi did
lives up to the world
and his deceased mother.
He has no regrets. And you should
not regret on his behalf either.
God.
Xi seeks justice
for his biological mother,
and yet he faces execution,
while that ruthless man
had been high-ranking and well-paid
for 20 years.
Is there
any justice in this world?
Stop walking around.
You're making me dizzy.
Cousin, do you think that Chamberlain Ren
can really persuade the Empress Dowager?
Can he really do so?
- Say something.
- Master.
- In the palace…
- What happened in the palace?
I got news from it.
The Empress Dowager summoned
Left Remonstrator Wang's child
under two and his mother
to enter the palace.
They are discussing the case
of Yuanming suing his father.
Why would the Empress Dowager
summon a toddler to the palace?
- Call me.
- Come here.
- Father.
Your Majesty.
He really is a prodigy.
Without formal education,
he already knows to respect the father.
Yes, indeed.
- Yes, indeed.
- Yes.
Mother.
Now, you have seen it too.
Du Yangxi's defense
indeed fails to convince the public.
Honoring fathers adheres to morality.
No exceptions for him.
Your Highness.
May I borrow something from you?
What do you wish to borrow?
The fresh peach from your table.
Thank you for your kindness.
Xingxing.
Come here.
- Mother.
- Hurry up.
- Help him up.
- Don't cry.
- It's okay. Don't cry.
Mr. Wang, in order to please you,
your concubine deliberately made the child
- call you first, right?
- Well…
Your Highness, please forgive me.
I am sorry.
A mother's grace is profound and vast.
Even a child under two years old
understands this,
while all the learned scholars here
turn a blind eye to this.
In all ages,
the father is upright and tall,
and the mother is loving and kind.
Both fathers and mothers
should be honored equally.
You only honor your father
but not your mother.
Do you all here not have kind mothers?
Has the Song
become a country without mothers?
We realize our mistakes.
Your Highness, please forgive us.
Please stand up.
Du Yangxi, you sued for your mother,
which is an act of filial piety.
You should be pardoned
and have your official position restored.
Emperor, what do you think?
Mother, you are right.
Your Highness, you are wise and sagacious.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
PEACE AND PROSPERITY
What an evil woman!
Go.
She's his wife.
Exiled for 2,000.
She got what she deserved.
- What an evil woman!
- Exactly.
Mother.
Hurry up.
Bad woman.
Throw it at her.
- She deserves to die.
- Yes.
Bad woman.
Throw at her.
Just throw at her.
- She should have been imprisoned long ago.
- Right.
- Is that the Yu family's carriage?
- It is the Yu family's carriage.
- Throw at him.
- Hurry up and go.
Throw at him.
Hurry up. Get out of the city gate.
- Let's go.
- She deserves it.
SIFU HOUSE
Madam, I am grateful for your kindness
over this period
for seeking physicians and medicine
for my mother and offering consolation
and saving my mother's and my life.
These are just some here, and I have sent
some silks to your house.
Hope you all can accept them.
Hearing you say this,
as if I do good deeds to expect something
in return from you.
When I was in jail,
it was all thanks to you taking care
of my stepmother and wife.
If you do not mind, I am willing
to marry into the Li family.
- Marry into the Li family?
- From now on, I will serve
and take care of you with Shouhua,
to inherit the Li family's traditions.
What?
Oh my. Mr. Du says he wants
to marry into the Li family.
Let me see.
Oh no.
Mother will definitely accept it.
Do you really want
to marry into the Li family?
I have already asked my stepmother,
and she totally agreed.
Everyone here, please be witness for me.
All I, Du Yangxi, have said today
is sincere.
Otherwise, I would be condemned.
Madam Li, no matter
what happened in the past,
Mr. Du is publicly apologizing to you.
What's there to hesitate about?
Yes. He is willing
to marry into your family.
You can get a son-in-law and a son.
You are reaping the rewards
of your good deeds.
- Yes.
- Indeed.
- Yes, indeed.
- Right.
Too late. You are one step too late.
The Sang family is coming
to send the betrothal gifts today.
Someone has beaten him to it.
Oh no, I must go and inform Shouhua.
No, no.
Madam Li.
The Sang family comes with betrothal
gifts. Come on. Bring them in.
- Drive them out.
- Yes.
- What are you doing, Mr. Du?
- Get out.
- Back off.
- What are you doing?
- We're here to…
- We bring betrothal gifts.
- Get out.
- What do you mean?
- I…
- Carry them in.
- Yes.
- No one is allowed in.
Let us in.
- Mr. Sang has said it.
- Go away.
- Get out.
- Let us in.
- Don't push us.
- Back off.
- Let us in.
- Make way.
- How could you?
Don't block us. Make way.
- Let us in. Let go of me.
- Move aside.
Are you determined to face death?
You even abandoned your sick stepmother.
How filial you are.
Shouhua loves you so much,
yet you divorced her.
I'll beat you, you ungrateful man!
Good.
- Well done.
- Shouhua.
Shouhua. The two are fighting now.
- The two?
- The two brothers-in-law.
No, it's the future brother-in-law
fighting with the former brother-in-law.
You and I are sworn brothers
and best friends for life,
yet you cut ties with me.
You were being unjust to me.
These three punches today
can repay all I owe you.
Have your people
take back the betrothal gifts.
You entrusted her to me
and now you want her back.
What do you take me for?
What do you take Shouhua for?
I didn't want to implicate her.
You know she is my beloved wife,
yet you still dare make a betrothal.
You had your eye on her long ago.
You are not that decent, anyway.
This is the Li family's house.
Fight outside. Don't make a mess here.
Shouhua has said
what is done cannot be undone.
From now on, you and her part ways.
Mr. Du, please do not pester any further.
Mr. Sang,
Shouhua invites you to talk in the hall.
Mr. Du, please leave.
- Mr. Sang, actually, I--
- You left the Du family in sorrow.
When you were in desperation,
I came to propose to you
and solve a dilemma for the Li family.
Do you still remember that?
You are generous and kind,
and what you've done is upright.
You offered help to us in a crisis,
and I am really grateful.
I'm glad you are not here
to call off the engagement.
I must return to my position tomorrow.
The next time we meet will be the wedding.
I'd like you to see me off. Is that okay?
Okay.
Yuanming.
Kangning has mentioned to me before
that Shouhua
seems soft but is actually stubborn.
It's not easy to persuade her.
Besides, the Sang and Li families
have already made a betrothal.
The wedding is settled.
Let go.
Oh no.
Mr. Sang is cunning. He deceived Shouhua
to go with him to his new position.
Why haven't we arrived
after such a long way?
Didn't your master say
to meet in the suburbs?
COUNTY BOUNDARY
I'm asking you. You are quite strange.
Sangma.
Mr. Sang.
Back when I was in humble circumstances,
Yuanming and I would often pretend
to be each other's servants.
I haven't worn this outfit
for a long time.
I think he should be arriving soon.
Who is he?
Mr. Sang, why?
In the wind and snow of that year,
a kind passerby gave me a chance to live.
I often think,
if I could see her once more,
I'd spend my life leading her horse
and guarding her to repay her kindness.
Unfortunately,
no matter how far this road goes,
it eventually comes to an end.
Mr. Sang.
Shouhua, I'm going back.
Let's call off the engagement.
Thank you for seeing me off.
Shouhua, you didn't go with him.
Sangma, I had enough rest. Let's go home.
Shouhua.
I was wrong. Please forgive me.
What wrong have you done?
You saw me as a burden,
blocking your way to filial obligations.
Now that you're back with high ranks
and boundless prospects,
you can just find a better wife.
Shouhua.
I was cold-hearted,
full of schemes and calculations,
and didn't know what love was.
Only after we met did I understand
what torture it is to miss someone.
Knowing you to marry another
is truly killing me
and leaves me in so much pain.
Now I was lucky to escape death.
If I had to let go of you again,
I'd rather die on the execution ground.
If you really want to leave me,
then I shall kneel forever.
After a thousand years,
I'd become a stone, pining for my wife,
letting everyone know
how ruthless you are
- to leave me.
- I…
You laughed at me for kneeling to a woman.
Come and see who is kneeling now.
Mr. Du, you ran so fast.
Sorry, sorry.
I just used a trick to make you anxious.
Don't panic.
Shouhua is here to see Mr. Sang off.
Shut up!
Get up.
Shouhua, I didn't want to come.
It's…
Kangning, it hurts so much.
Come out now.
Mr. Du is so sincere.
Shouhua, please forgive him.
Let them watch. I am not afraid,
even if everyone watches me.
If I ever dare to lie to you again
or make you upset,
then you'd punish me to be a slave.
No.
Punish me to be that.
I shall not be a human anymore
and will only listen to you.
Shouhua, my wife.
Please forgive me.
- Stop it.
- Mr. Du, get up now.
Shouhua has already forgiven you.
Really?
You!
Get up. Get up now.
Long live my wife!
That's great.
- What's wrong, Fuhui?
- Fuhui, stop. Mother isn't here.
It seems to be real this time.
Fuhui!
- Fuhui!
- Well…
- What to do?
- What should we do?
- Hurry.
What to do?
Call the physician!
- Let's take her home first.
- Hang in there, Fuhui.
BIANJING, THE TWELFTH MONTH
Master, over here, over here.
Over here, over here.
SIFU HOUSE
Bodhisattva.
Bodhisattva, bless my Joy
with health and a robust body.
Bless my Leshan and Haode
find an ideal husband soon.
Bless Sifu House with customers flocking
and making a fortune every day.
Thank you for your blessings.
Bodhisattva, I wish
my competitors be unlucky in everything.
May they stumble as they walk
and travel.
I'm not done. Can the Bodhisattva
hear me at such a distance?
Master Liu, you are late today.
We have new tea arriving today.
Would you like to try?
As usual.
- Qibao pounded tea, no ginger.
- Alright.
One distinguished guest.
Master Liu is here.
- Spacious seats inside.
- Okay.
Is Joy's golden lock ready yet?
Don't delay the good day.
It has been replaced long ago.
Look at you. You've asked
several times this morning.
Who dare delay your granddaughter's
banquet for 100-day birthday?
This is the first grandchild
of the Li family.
My precious.
Her banquet for turning 100-day-old
is the most important.
Understood.
Mother, some kitchenware
and the old tea sets need to be replaced.
Okay, okay.
From now on, you can make the decisions
on these trivial matters.
- Sifu House.
- Let's go.
Mother.
- Keep calm.
- They…
Aunt. Aunt.
- I wish you all the best.
- Aunt, you are doing well.
I haven't seen you for two years.
I've been looking for you.
Greetings, Aunt.
- Greetings, Aunt.
- Greetings.
What are you here for?
I had the lamp maker craft this specially.
There is a chubby baby inside.
This is carved exactly to resemble Joy.
Do you think it's funny
to hold it on the head
on the Lantern Festival?
Haode.
The Fan family is a family of wealth,
and Fuhui's mother-in-law is quite picky.
They will laugh at you for being childish.
You're the one who's being childish.
Look at mine.
This was made by the best goldsmith
I could find.
The jade rabbit worshiping the moon.
Joy is a little rabbit.
- Leshan, mind your words.
- Here.
Shouhua, listen.
You've been spoiled by us.
Whenever you go out,
you can't be so capricious.
I am not capricious.
If we make this
about the size of a walnut
and then pin some
beautiful pearls and jade here,
sprinkle with floral fragrance,
would it be nice to wear it on the head
for the Lantern Festival?
Yes, and it can also be changed to a peony
to sell at our shop.
But if you wear this on the head, what if
you accidentally set your hair on fire?
Next year, you would be bald.
Then you would be the most conspicuous.
You would be bald. Give it back to me.
- Hurry.
- Alright. Here you are.
Who are you? How can you barge in here?
You can't go in.
No, I must see Madam Li.
- The master hasn't spoken.
- We're here for family.
- Move.
- I want to see Madam Li.
I'll go announce your arrival.
- Please wait here.
- Madam Li.
No way.
Madams.
They insisted on barging in.
I've tried to prevent them.
So rude.
The maid is ignorant. Please forgive us.
May I ask
where you are from?
Are you related to the Li family?
- We…
- Shouhua.
We know every relative of the Li family.
The two of them look somewhat unfamiliar.
Perhaps they have gone to the wrong place.
- Do you recognize them?
- No.
Youlong, come and pay your respects.
This is the eldest sister, Shouhua.
This is the third sister, Kangning.
This must be the fourth sister, Haode.
Haode, Leshan. Come greet your sisters.
Shouhua, Kangning, Haode, Leshan.
As the younger brother,
I pay my respect to you all.
Younger brother?
- Brother.
- Aunt, it smells good.
- Put it here.
Have some soup.
After such a long journey,
finally, we've made it to the capital.
Serve all the good food and drinks now.
- Serve whatever good drinks you have.
- Hurry up.
Right, moreover,
I have a hearty appetite. Bring me
another three bowls of soaked rice.
The fried kidneys are really delicious.
This one.
I want to have some soup.
Tell me. What are you here for?
You are the big brother. You…
You are running
such a big store in Bianjing.
Obviously, you've made it big.
Considering the favor
of the deceased Fourth Uncle,
you should take care of us,
the poor nephews, right?
- Right?
- Yes, take care of us.
How dare you mention Fourth Uncle here!
Each one of you has lands and properties
in your hometown,
yet you still wanted to usurp
my family's assets.
Less than two years since he passed away,
you've taken everything from his house.
All sixteen chests and cages
and all the porridge bowls and ladles.
You've even taken away
the rice cooking on the stove.
Do you even consider yourselves human?
- I…
- Leave now.
Well, don't make a scene.
We are all clan relatives, all connected.
We share the common ancestry.
We should help each other.
Now you are rich and honored,
but we are still enduring hunger and cold.
- Right.
- Yes.
Besides, Fourth Uncle
had been treating us well.
- Yes.
- Everyone in the clan heard his last words
before he passed away.
The words still echo in our ears.
Aunt, you can't go back on us, can you?
- No.
- Then it's great.
No way! Get out!
Get out. Get out of here.
- Mother.
- Get out.
Get lost.
Don't take the nonsense
they said to heart.
- I'm so mad.
- Mother.
As your son, I kowtow to you.
Having endured hardship all the way here
and we mother and son
have finally seen you.
- Madam Li.
- Stop it.
Madam, you are…
Madam Li,
I am the servant girl, Cai Wujie.
In the past, I served Master.
He used to call me Ah Cai.
So many years have passed,
and I've grown old,
so my appearance has changed a bit.
Please take a closer look again.
Ah Cai.
Mother, this Madam Cai says
to bring her son to find his origin.
She says this young man,
who also has the surname Li,
is Father's son.
Yes.
- Mother.
- Mother, wake up.
- Wake up.
- Mother, get some tea.
- What should we do?
Fan her, Mother.
Mother, wake up.
- Chunlai.
- The tea is here.
- Hurry up, Haode.
- Haode.
- You're awake, Mother.
- Take it slow.
If he really had a son,
you'd never come to pay respect
during the festivals and his birthdays.
When he died, you'd never come
to visit his grave.
Afterward, the Li family had no inheritor.
Relatives quarreling over assets,
and you'd never come to support us.
And now, at this time, you show up
and want to take advantage of me.
Get out, out!
I was pregnant when I got married.
- Out!
- Master was scared of you,
so he didn't want my son
to come find his origin.
Everything I say is the truth.
Get out, get out!
- Get out!
- We should ask her clearly, Mom.
- Open the door.
Madam Li, please open the gate.
My son and I have no place to stay.
Please be kind.
Please spare Youlong,
Master's only son left in this world.
Can you at least give us a place to stay?
This family is full of ruthless women.
Don't beg them.
Son, kneel down
and beg Madam Li to let you in
to offer incense to your father.
Then consider it
to fulfill his filial piety.
We have gone through hardship
and almost died on the way here.
- Mother. Mother, don't cry.
- Madam Li.
Since they refuse to acknowledge me,
let's report to the Yamen.
Subtitle translation by: Wina Huang